Snehith Kongara

214-892-7425 | snehith529@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/kongara-snehith/ Portfolio Website https://snehith529.github.io/snehithkongara/

Professional Summary

Software developer with nearly 3 years of experience, specializing in building microservice-based solutions using Spring Boot. Skilled in designing and implementing predictive models utilizing machine learning and deep learning technologies.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Python, C, R, SQL

Artificial Intelligence : Machine learning algorithms, Convolution Neural Networks (CNN), Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) Other tools & Softwares : Camunda, AWS, GitLab, Mayen, JIRA, SonarQube, Testing(Unit, Integration, E2E), Eclipse, Tableau

Professional Experience

The University of Texas at Arlington (UTA)

Arlington, TX

Graduate Teaching Assistant (GTA)

Aug 2024 – Dec 2024

June 2023 – Aug 2024

Assist students with tutoring and addressing their concerns in database systems and MySQL

The University of Texas at Arlington Research Institute (UTARI)

Fort Worth, TX

Research Assistant

- Automated data collection processes for proprietary medical data by writing Python scripts
- Visualized data using **Tableau** to extract insights and support decision-making
- Designed and implemented machine learning (ML) and deep learning (DL) models for posture detection using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM), and hybrid models (CNN+LSTM)

Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

Hyderabad, India

Software Engineer – Java Developer

July 2021 - Dec 2022

- Achieved a 5% boost in system scalability by developing microservices using SpringBoot framework in Java
- Orchestrated orders with Camunda, resulting in 10% reduction in fulfillment time and improved system efficiency by 10%
- Processed the request XMLs, and sent the responses to the downstream systems during REST API calls using Postman
- Developed using Test driven development (TDD) tested with Junit, Mockito & improved the code quality using SonarQube
- Used version control tool GitLab and maintained a 95% defect-free rate, leading to a 20% decrease in post-release issues
- Orchestrated CI/CD pipelines for each microservice using Kubernetes, leveraging Dockerfiles for containerization

Indian Servers

Vijayawada, India

Machine Learning Engineer – Internship

May 2020 - June 2021

- Utilized generative adversarial networks (GANs) and transfer learning techniques to implement solutions in deep learning
- Achieved a model accuracy of 90% through the development and training of deep learning models using TensorFlow
- Experimented with various data preprocessing and feature engineering techniques for linear regression, logistic regression, random forests, & neural networks, resulting in reducing noise and improving the overall reliability of ML models

Projects

Brain Tumor Classification Using Deep Learning Network – Github Brain Tumor

- Developed a deep learning model to detect tumors using Brain MRI images using ResNet-50 features.
- Tech Stack/ Libraries: CNN, TensorFlow, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Python

$\textbf{Detection Of Fake Satellite Images Using Deep Learning} - \underline{Github-Detection-of-fake-satellite-images} \\$

- Developed a deep learning model to detect fake satellite images using specialized hand-crafted features & ResNet50 features
- Tech Stack/ Libraries: GAN, NumPy, Pandas, Python

Publications

Detection And Classification of Lung Cancer Using Vgg-16 – IEEE Published Paper

- Developed a machine learning model that detects Lung Cancer using VGG-16
- Predict Malignant tumors in early stages of tumor with accuracy of 88%
- Tech Stack/ Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, Python

CERTIFICATIONS

- AI Programming with Python Udacity
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Certification AWS CCP
- 98-381: MTA: Introduction to Programming Using Python by Microsoft Python

Education

University of Texas, Arlington, TX, USA

Jan 2023 - Dec 2024

GPA: **3.91/4.0**

Master's, Computer Science

Courses

Neural Networks, Cloud Computing, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Data Analytics, Distributed Systems, Data Mining, Data Analytics and Modelling Techniques, Database Systems, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Statistics with R, Data Structures